Charles A. and June R. P. Ross Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Charles A. and June R. P. Ross Archives
1953-2002
IPAR.001254
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
2
The archives of Charles A. and June R. P. Ross. These include maps, field notebooks, and photographs.
Ross, Charles Alexander
Biographical Sketch
June Rosa Pitt Ross was born May 2, 1931 in Taree, NSW, Australia. She went to the University of Sydney to earn a BSc, PhD, and DSc. She did post-doctoral work under an AAUW (American Association of University Women) scholarship at Yale University (and Peabody Museum of Natural History). June taught biology at Western Washington University from 1967-2004. She was active in both the International Association of Bryozoologists and the Paleontological Society.
Charles Alexander Ross was born 16 Apr 1933 in Champaign, IL. He completed a BA at the University of Colorado before coming to Yale University for his PhD. He worked for a few years at the Illinois State Geological Survey before joining the geology faculty at Western Washington University in 1964. His work focuses primarily on Pennsylvanian-Permian foraminifera and their use in biostratigraphy.
Description of the Material
Includes photocopies of field notebooks from Charlie Ross (Glass Mountains), locality information pertaining to Charlie's fusulinid localities and June's bryozoan localities, photographs and negatives of specimens, and miscellaneous documents.
Connecticut; USA; Washington; Australia; England; Texas; New York; Vermont; Locality information; Photographs; Negatives; Reprints; Field notebooks; Maps; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Locality Information, Series I
  - Field Notebooks., 001258
    - Field notes. Field notebook for 1995 Central States field trip (book 1 of 2), 12 May 1995 - 25 May 1995; 003201
    - Field notes. Field notebook for 1998 Central States field trip (book 2 of 2), 17 Jun 1998 - 29 Jun 1998; 003200
    - Field notes. Field notebook (photocopy) for Glass Mt, Pennsylvanian and Permian (notebook 1): Texas., 1957; 000315
    - Field notes. Field notebook for Appalachian field trip (October 7, 1958) and also for Ordovician Chazy, Crown Point trip (July 21, 1960 - July 31, 1960), 1958-1960; 003197
    - Field notes. Field notebook (photocopy) for Glass Mt, Texas Pennsylvanian and Permian: Texas., 1959; 000318
    - Field notes. Field notebook for France and England trip. 1973., 003198
    - Field notes. Central States (Ohio, Indiana, Wisconsin, Iowa, Minnesota, Kentucky), June Ross coll. of May-June, 1995; & some 1998; Nevada, June, 1995, 000838
    - Field notes. Central States (Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kentucky, Minnesota, Missouri, Ohio, Tennessee), J. Ross coll. of 1998; Bryozoa, 000839
    - Field notes. Field notebook for 1974 trip to England, 25 Aug 1974 - 22 Sep 1974; 003203
    - Field notes. Field notebook for 1995 Central States field trip (book 2 of 2), 26 May 1995 - 14 Jun 1995; 003202
    - Field notes. Field notebook for 1998 Central States field trip (book 1 of 2), 29 May 1998 - 16 Jun 1998; 003199
    - Field notes. Field notes of June Ross - August and September 1972., 000935
    - Locality information. Field notebook (photocopy) for Glass Mt, Texas; Pennsylvanian and Permian (notebook 2, in 2 parts): and Hueco Mt. (p.134). 1957, 1958, 000316
    - Locality information. Texas, Late Pennsylvanian Shelf Sediments; Field Guide; C.A Ross locs 4-12-69 thru 4-13-69, 1969; 000847
    - Charles A. Ross - 1995 - Field notes and locality information for one section (Jakes Canyon, S of Rt. 50) in White Pine County, Nevada, including stratigraphy details and collection events., 18 Jun 1995; 002915
    - Field notes of Charles A. Ross. Field Notebook #1, June-July 1957, Glass Mountains and Marathon Basin, West Texas Study of Wolfcampian Series, Lower Permian. Original field notes and typed transcript of notes [transcribed by E.M. Koshko]. Also includes reference list of publications by C.A. Ross and J.R.P. Ross which used localities from the notebook., 003087
    - June Ross locality notes describing sites around the Cincinnati Arch region collected in 1958 (OH, KY, IN)., 002747
    - June Ross locality notes describing sites collected in September of 1958 (Tennessee)., 003195
    - June Ross field notes for Indiana - 1961, 1964; also information about Ft. Wayne cores., 002748
    - June Ross - 3.5' floppy disk containing four sets of field notes - 1961 (Nov), 1962/1963, 1963, and 1964. These files were produced in ClarisWorks 4.0. They were retrieved from the diskette on July 12, 2017, but there are some formatting issues. The notes were saved as pdfs. Paper copies are stored with the diskette; pdfs are attached here as Multimedia records., 1961-1964; 002749
    - June and Charles Ross locality notes. Field Book #1, July 1962 - MI, MN, WI. Original field notes, xerox of field notes, typed transcript of notes. Also includes typed copies of Rifle Hill and Cummingsville sections from 1956 GSA Guidebook., 002750
    - Field notes of June Ross - May-June 1964; TN & KY. Original field notes and a typed set., 002927
    - Field notes of Charles A. Ross. Field Notebook #2, 1957-1958, Glass Mountains and Marathon Basin, West Texas Study of Wolfcampian Series, Lower Permian. Original field notes and typed transcript of notes [transcribed by E.M. Koshko]., 003092
    - Field notes of Charles A. Ross and June R.P. Ross. Field Notebook #3, 1959-1964, Glass Mountains and Marathon Basin, West Texas Study of Leonardian Series (mainly), Lower Permian; Salt River Section, Arizona, 1964; Ordovician, Oklahoma. Original field notes and typed transcript of notes [transcribed by E.M. Koshko]; few stratigraphic columns with sedimentary structures; note of info on a taxonomy/ecology expert from W. Germany., 003095
    - 1982-1983. Field notes and locality information for various Penn/Perm sections in Nevada completed or visited by Charles A. Ross., 002918
    - 1991. Field notes and locality information for many Penn/Perm sections measured in Nevada between July-August 1991., 002916
    - 2002. Field notes and locality information for seven Nevada Penn/Perm sections, including Grindstone Mountain, E. Elko Radio Tower, Garden Pass (re-written notes from 7 Sep 1960 and "another try" notes dated 8 Sep 2002), E flank Diamond Range (Riva's Locs), Thompson Ranch, Secret Canyon and Carlin Canyon sections., 002914
    - Field notes of June Ross - 1963 - central states. Xerox of field notes and typed copies., 003176
  - Locality Information: USA., 001257
    - Catalog of localities. Fusulinid Catalog of localities of various Peabody fusuline collections: North America, Europe, Asia., 1960; 000252
    - Locality information. Locality information and correspondence; Robert Blodgett's material from Farewell Mountain, AK, 09 Dec 1983; 002731
    - Locality information. June Ross: log of New York field trip May 21-27, 1958 and field notebook., 002926
    - Locality information. Locality information: June Ross, northeastern New York, Vermont., 1959-1960; 000497
    - Locality information. Measured sections (typed) for Glass Mt, Pennsylvanian and Permian: Texas., 1959; 000319
    - Locality information. Mt Stephens Burgess Sh locality map & locality numbers for Glass Mt late Pennsylvanian: British Columbia, Canada, Texas., 1959; 000320
    - Locality information. Locality information: Texas. 196?, 1960; 000183
    - Locality information. Collecting Localities for C.A. Ross Dissertation: Texas., 1960; 000251
    - Locality information. Locality information: June Ross, Central States (Minnesota, Ohio, Wisconsin) - site descriptions and a map with an overlay identifying localities., 1962-1964; 002744
    - Locality information. Locality information: June Ross, Notes from the GSA Field Guidebook of 1956 denoting collections made 7-15-62 and 5-13-95, 1962; 003194
    - Locality information. Locality information: northwestern New York, Ontario., 1964; 000178
    - Locality information. Locality information: Nevada. Permian., 1964; 000185
    - Locality information. Arizona, New Mexico; Pennsylvanian, Permian. 1965, 1966, 1968, 000180
    - Locality information. Arizona; Pennsylvanian, Permian. 1965, 1966. Boxes 5 & 6 & 7, 000182
    - Locality information. Kansas, Pennsylvanian (coll. 11/2, 11/3, 11/6, 11/7/1965), Fusulinacea, 000828
    - Locality information. Locality & faunal descriptions: Alaska., 1977; 000184
    - Locality information. Kansas, Oklahoma, Pennsylvanian, Permian; Field Guide; C.A. Ross locs., 1998, 000837
    - Locality information. locality information; bryozoa and fusulinids colls. 1963-1998; notes on location of colls. in 218 KGL & 281 ESC; blank drawer labels; [most docs now split up into separate documents; C.MacC., 2006], 2002; 000768
    - Locality information. Locality information and correspondence; Bolivian bryozoans from Wayne Pryor, 000975
    - Locality information. Locality information and correspondence; Two well slides from Palo Pinto County, TX via Tom Yancey, 000976
    - Locality information. Locality information: cores held at the Illinois State Geological Survey. Central states core data from Illinois for the following cores: C234, C960, C2241, C2281, C2374, C2380, C2515, C2534, C2591, C2626, C2627, C2628, C2662, C2663, C2695, C2696, C2713, C2740, C2749, C2751, C2759, C2759, C2788, C2794, C2857, C2859, C2864, C2905, C2910, C2916, C2945, C2949, C2972, C3095, C3224, C3229, C3230, C3282, C3323, C3340, C3365, C3375, C3378, C3384, C3445, C3477, C3495, C3518, C3520, C3525, C3531, C3537, C3556, C3592, C3757, C3783, C3903, C3904, C3906, C3907, C3956, C3960, C3963, C3966, C3967, C3970, C3975, C3978, C3987, C3989, C4100, C4213, C4214, C4240, C4312, C4495, 15419, 002730
    - Miscellaneous. Catalog of box descriptions: Arizona, New Mexico. 1953, 1954, 1962. Boxes 1,2,3,4, 000181
    - Paul Thompson Bryozoa. Correspondence about a series of slides given to June Ross from an undergraduate project carried out by Paul Thompson. Also includes a xerox of the report., 1969-1975; 002416
    - Assorted maps and pamphlets from June Ross' 1956 GSA field trip to Michigan, Wisconsin, Minnesota. Also includes a 1995 map of MN from a return trip. Not annotated., 1962-1995; 002759
    - Notes on Ordovician Cincinnati Arch bryozoan occurrences from the literature, notes for lectures about the Cincinnati Arch region including stratigraphic sections and overhead transparencies, 1995-1998; 002877
    - Assorted maps and pamphlets from the Cincinnati Arch region. Includes a downtown map of Cincinnati, OH, pamphlets and maps for Little Miami State Park (OH) and Caesar Creek State Park (OH), Elizabethtown, KY pamphlet/map, Kentucky's Outdoor Wonderland - Lake Cumberland, Dale Hollow Lake, Green River Lake, Big South Fork National Park - booklet/maps. Not annotated., 1995; 002732
    - Three copies of "Map of Highbridge and Trenton Areas - showing location of mineral veins" from Miller, A. M. 1905. "The lead and zinc bearing rocks of central Kentucky." Kentucky Geological Survey Bulletin 2, p.1-34. One copy is hand-colored by June Ross to show the exposures of Cincinnati-age rocks and Highbridge-age rocks., 002876
    - Locality information. Mostly lists of cores from Illinois that June studied. Most of the cores have C numbers, a few have J numbers, and a few are just five digit numbers. Each core has TRS data listed with it; some have the depth of Silurian or Devonian rocks listed. Also includes a list of depths at which Permian bryozoan were found in C2485, and photo negatives of Ordovician and Silurian core data from southern Illinois., 002920
    - Locality information for cores from the Humble Oil Company in Michigan, 002921
    - Locality information for cores from the Illinois Natural Gas & Storage Company: IL, Piatt Co., J, Buchan #1; IL, Champaign Co., R. S. Hinton #1; IA, Dubuque Co., A. Jordan #1., 002922
    - Indiana Tourguide Map published by Gulf Oil Co., localities of cores from Northern Indiana Public Service Co. circled on map, 002923
    - Locality information for cores from the Northern Indiana Public Storage Company (Holes 2, 4, 27, 45) and some information on other Indiana cores including those with FW numbers., 002924
  - Locality Information: outside the USA., 003206
    - Antofagasta, Chile. Correspondence, photographs, and reprints related to a collection of bryozoans sent by Christoph Breitkreuz to June Ross; collected in Antofagasta Region, Chile., 1985-1986; 001386
    - Card file. Card catalog of Bryozoa localities for Anticosti Island collections: Quebec., 1959; 000325
    - Locality information. Locality data. Australia: Attunga district fossils collected by Dr. I. Brown in 1942; a description of the Gordon Limestone of Tasmania by Maxwell Banks; Hatter's Corner; Hill 1951; geological sketch map of the Yass-Taemas district; geological sketch map of the Attunga district; geological sketch map of the Molong-Manildra district; geological sketch map of the Wellington district; geological map of the Clarencetown Paterson district., 1942-1960; 003207
    - Locality information. Notes regarding Yass and Canberra including: Geological excursion to Yass programme: 1954; Geological excursion to Yass programme: 1956; This Week in Canberra, no.44; A.N.Z.A.A.S. Canberra Meeting, 1954., 1954-1956; 003208
    - Locality information. Donets Basin (Ukraine), Bashkiria (south Urals, Russia [USSR]), Pennsylvanian, Permian (locs 9/1975), Fusulinacea, 000829
    - Locality information. England; Internat. Bryozoa Assoc. Conf., J. & C. Ross coll. 9-7 to 9-13, 1980, 000840
    - Locality information. Japan, Permian, 5 lots of Fusulinacea, 000834
    - Locality information. Locality information and correspondence; Darwin's locality at Maria Island, near Hobart, Tasmania, 000972
    - Locality information. Locality information and correspondence; Eigel Nielson's Central East Greenland collection, 000973
    - Locality information. Locality information and correspondence; Curt Teichert's Central East Greenland collection, 000974
    - Locality information. Locality information and correspondence; Australian bryozoans from John Laurie, 000977
    - Locality information. Locality information and correspondence; Austrian Himalayas Expedition of Gerhard Fuchs, 000978
    - Rio Cachin, Venezuela. Correspondence and photographs related to an etched sample sent by Peter Hoover to June Ross; collected near Rio Cachin, Estado Zulia, Venezuela, 1983-1985; 001387
    - Zafar Shaikh Bryozoa. Correspondence about a series of slides given to June Ross from the thesis of Zafar Shaikh (IPR.09689). Also includes xeroxes of pertinent sections of the thesis, and a hand-colored geological map., 1970-1976; 001388
  - Maps., 002879
    - Block Map. Trans-Pecos Abstract Company - 1939-1951 - Block [Abstract] Map of Brewster County, Texas. 1951 Revised Version. No Scale., 003018
    - Block Map. Land Survey Plate from John Stovell, Licensed Land Survey of Brewster County, Texas - 1939 - Zoomed-in block [Abstract] map of Brewster County, Texas. Annotated and shaded where wells may have been logged and/or land was owned by Chevron Corporation in 1990, respectively (See Associations Tab)., 003019
    - Geologic Map & Cross Section. Publication Material (Text Fig. 15) from C.A. Ross' Standard Wolfcampian Series (published 1963). Scale: 1:63360. Probably related to a larger, photocopied version containing a similar 2' Lat/Long grid [see Associations tab]. Not annotated with Localities., 1959-1961; 003058
    - Geologic Map and Cross Sections. 1964 - USGS Geologic Map and Sections of the Frenchie Creek Quadrangle, Nevada. Scale 1:62500. Not annotated with localities; published in USGS Bulletin 1173, 003170
    - Geologic Map and Cross Sections. 1971 - USGS Geologic Map of the Swales Mountain Quadrangle and Part of the Adobe Summit Quadrangle, Elko County, Nevada. Scale 1:24000. Not annotated with localities., 003169
    - Geologic Map. Bureau of Economic Geology (UT Austin) - Geologic Map of the Glass Mountains, Brewster and Pecos counties, Texas. Scale: 1:63360. Photocopy of original (which may have been mounted on canvas [see straight, white, gridded blank zones]. Not annotated with localities., 1925-1927; 003057
    - Geologic Map. Nure Aerial Gamma Ray and Magnetic Reconnaissance Survey Geologic Base Map - Big Bend, Texas-Marfa NH13-5 Quadrangle, Prepared for the Department of Energy. Scale: 1:250000. Not annotated with localities., 1978; 003060
    - Geologic Map. Nure Aerial Gamma Ray and Magnetic Reconnaissance Survey Geologic Base Map - Big Bend, Texas-Ft. Stockton NH13-6 Quadrangle, Prepared for the Department of Energy. Scale: 1:250000. Not annotated with localities., 1978; 003061
    - Geologic Map. Bureau of Economic Geology (UT Austin) - 2x1 degree Geologic Atlas of Texas, Fort Stockton Sheet, Charles Laurence Bake Memorial Edition. Accompanying the map is a detailed legend packet. Scale: 1:250000. Not annotated with localities., 1982; 003062
    - Geologic Map. 1960. Geologic Map of East Central Nevada, published as a field trip map, published within the1960 Field Conference run jointly by the Intermountain Association of Petroleum Geologists and Eastern Nevada Geological Society. Scale 1:192000. Not annotated with localities., 003178
    - Geologic Map. 1960-1967. Geology of the O'Neil Pass Area, Elko County, Nevada. Scale: 1:31680. Photocopy of original. Not annotated with localities; this geologic map is likely part of a publication (yet to be identified)., 003163
    - Geologic Map. Geologic Map of the Northern Part of the Snake Mountains, Elko County, Nevada. Scale: 1:63360. Photocopy of original (which may have been modified by C.A. Ross). Not annotated with localities; this geologic map is Plate 3 of some (as of yet unidentified) publication, using a topographic base at scale 1:250,000., 003161
    - Geologic Map. 1967. Geologic Outline Map of Northern Independence Range, Nevada. Scale: 1:62500. Photocopy of original. Not annotated with localities; this geologic map is Plate 1 of Churkin and Kay (1967; see Associations Tab)., 003162
    - Geologic Map. 1973. US Geological Survey - Preliminary Geologic Map of the hUNTER Quadrangle, Elko County, Nevada [By K. B. Ketner]. Scale: 1:24000. Not annotated with localities., 003165
    - Geologic Map. 1974. US Geological Survey - Preliminary Geologic Map of the Blue Basin Quadrangle, Elko County, Nevada [By K. B. Ketner]. Scale: 1:24000. Not annotated with localities., 003164
    - Geologic Map. 1978 - USGS and Nevada Bureau of Mines Co-Op - Geologic Map of Nevada. Scale ~1:500,000. Not annotated with localities; this map is partial, and is comprised of two of an unknown number of parts--map and key., 003171
    - Geologic Map. 1980 - USGS and Nevada Bureau of Mines Co-Op - Geologic Map of Lincoln County, Nevada. Scale ~1:250,000. Not annotated with localities; published by Nevada Bureau of Mines and Geology as "Geology and Mineral Deposits of Lincoln County, Plate 2.", 003168
    - Geologic Map. Marathon and Glass Mountains area, Texas. Scale Unknown. Photocopy of original map, annotated with outlines of specific geologic formations and [presumed] locales of interest for geologic investigation., 003053
    - Geologic Map. Marathon and Glass Mountains area, Texas. Scale: 1:63360. Photocopy of original map, with a 2-minute Lat/Long grid. Not annotated with localities., 003054
    - Geologic Map. Composite topographic map (composed of USGS 7.5' topographic quadrangles) spanning Dugout Mountain, Beckwith Hills and Marathon, Texas. Scale 1:24000. Photocopy of original map. Not annotated with localities., 003055
    - Geologic Map. USGS Geologic Map of Nevada. Scale ~1:1,500,000. Not annotated with localities; this map is partial, and is comprised of two of an unknown number of parts--map and key. Scale and date of publication are missing., 003172
    - Geologic Maps. Charles A. Ross - 1980-1985 - One index map of Nevada annotated with numbered zones corresponding with a geologic investigation, commissioned by Chevron Corp., conducted on Penn/Perm strata between ~1980-1985. This index is accompanied by 24 topographic maps [including one duplicate of Roberts Creek Mtn. quadrangle], some of which are cut, taped, marked and, in some cases, partially made into geologic maps., 003001
    - Gravity Map. 1991 - Lisle Exploration Company Gravity and Aeromagnetic Surveys of Nevada. Scale ~1:1,500,000. Not annotated with localities., 003173
    - Index to Topographic Maps of Texas. Index map for topographic maps in the Texas, USA. C.A. Ross wrote a contact number for obtaining maps from this index (in pencil). Not annotated with localities., 1979; 003056
    - Map. USGS 2 x 1 degree topographic map - Elko, Nevada. Revised 1972 version. Scale 1:250000. One annotation indicating the type section for the Pequop Fm is circled a bit east of N Center on the map. Not annotated with localities., 1955; 003003
    - Map. US BLM Public Lands Guide district maps for the Battle Mountain [1967], Carson City [1967], Elko [1966], Ely [1967], Las Vegas [1967] and Winnemucca [1967] areas of Nevada. Scale 1:500000. Not annotated with localities., 1966-1967; 003000
    - Map. Two official highway maps for the state of Nevada, one from 1991-1992 and the other from 1995-1996. Scale 1:500,000; one map of the Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forest [courtesy of the USDA Forest Service, 2000], covering the Mountain City and Jar Bridge ranger districts. None of the maps are annotated with localities., 1991-1996; 002999
    - Map. US BLM 30' x 60' Surface and Surface/Mineral Management maps for the Elko and Battle Mountain, Nevada areas, respectively. Scale 1:100000. Neither of these two maps is annotated with localities., 1996; 002998
    - Map. US Department of the Interior - Bureau of Indian Affairs, Phoenix Area Office, Branch of Forestry - Basemap with roads, fluvial traces and TRS coordinates - Fort Apache Indian Reservation, Arizona - Timber Survey, Unit 3. Scale: 2" = 1 mile. Drawing No. 232-3, 11 Feb 1963; 002836
    - Map. USGS 15' topographic quadrangle - Ray - Arizona. Scale 1:62500. 1910 Edition, reprinted in 1948. Not annotated with localities., 002814
    - Map. USGS 15' topographic quadrangle - Christmas - Arizona. Scale 1:62500. Not annotated with localities., 1915; 002793
    - Map. USGS 15' topographic quadrangle - Casa Grande - Arizona. Scale 1:62500. Not annotated with localities., 1922; 002792
    - Map. USGS 30' x 50' topographic quadrangle - Chisos Mountains, Texas. Scale 1:125000. 1905 edition, reprinted 1923. Mounted on canvas. Annotated with orange circles [reconnaissance purposes?] and a couple of penciled-in notes., 003043
    - Map. USGS 30' topographic quadrangle - Terlingua, Texas. Scale 1:125000. 1904 edition, reprinted 1926. Mounted on canvas. Annotated with one Big Bend collection [7-7-57-2]., 003050
    - Map. USGS 30' topographic quadrangle - Valentine, Texas. Scale 1:125000. 1897 edition, reprinted 1929. Mounted on canvas. Not annotated with localities., 003051
    - Map. Sixth edition map of Parish of Queanbeyan, County of Murray, Land district of Queanbeyan; Yarrowlumla shire & municipality of Queanbeyan, 1931; 003211
    - Map. USGS 15' topographic quadrangle - Camp Verde - Arizona. Scale 1:62500 - Datum NAD27. Not annotated with localities., 1932; 002791
    - Map. USGS advance sheet topographic quadrangle - Helena, Mich (NE quarter). Scale 1:31680. 1932 edition. Not annotated with localities., 002887
    - Map. USGS advance sheet topographic quadrangle - Helena, Mich (NW quarter). Scale 1:31680. 1932 edition. Not annotated with localities., 002888
    - Map. USGS advance sheet topographic quadrangle - Helena, Mich (SE quarter). Scale 1:31680. 1932 edition. Not annotated with localities., 002889